perrymarshall.com 2019-03-03

# Privacy | Perry Marshall

**Perry S. Marshall & Associates, Inc.** (“PSMA”) is an Illinois corporation, File Number 65222477. 

PSMA has established this Privacy Policy to explain how it protects and manages the personal information that it collects from you (the customer) online.

* **Consent for Collection, Use and Disclosure**

By visiting and browsing [perrymarshall.com](https://www.perrymarshall.com/) and/or by registering for PSMA products and services, you consent to the terms of and the practices disclosed within this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy, please do not use the PSMA site.

PSMA may occasionally update this Privacy Policy and will post the changes at this or another location specified here. Any inquiries regarding this Privacy Policy should be directed to [privacy@perrymarshall.com](mailto:privacy@perrymarshall.com).

At any time a customer may object to the processing of or may withdraw his or her consent for collection, use and disclosure of the “Data” (personal information and personally identifiable related website-visit data) collected from that customer. Please note that if you do, PSMA may suspend its provision of products and services to you. When you unsubscribe, if you fall within the guarantee period for any PSMA product and you request a refund, the guarantee will be honored.

To object to collection or processing of your Data, you need to contact PSMA in writing, either at the address disclosed near the end of this Policy document or via email to [privacy@perrymarshall.com](mailto:privacy@perrymarshall.com).

* **Accountability**

PSMA collects, at the time of your registration and your sign-on to its website and through third parties, certain Data (information that personally identifies you) that may include but is not limited to your name, email address, home or work address, telephone number, financial/credit card details, and information about your computer hardware and software (e.g., IP address, operating system, browser type, your login information, URLs you access on our site, access times, and referring website addresses).

Unless otherwise specified, all Data requested by or collected by PSMA is necessary for the provision of services to customers and users of PSMA’s websites. Any use of Cookies (see “[Cookies Policy](https://www.perrymarshall.com/cookies/)”) by PSMA’s websites is connected with the provision of services required by users and customers.

PSMA has implemented this Privacy Policy to protect Data received from its customers and to respond to any inquiries. The Privacy Policy also provides that PSMA will use appropriate contractual means to establish a comparable level of protection for Data which is sent for processing by third parties on PSMA’s behalf.

* **Third-party Vendors**

We use Google tracking and advertising products to provide and improve our advertising, including: Remarketing with Google Analytics, Google Display Network Impression Reporting, and Google Analytics Demographics & Interest Reporting.  
Google uses Cookies to display PSMA ads based on our visitors’ past visits to the PSMA website, other websites and their activity on google.com.

You may opt out of Google’s use of Cookies by visiting the [Google advertising opt-out page](http://www.google.com/privacy_ads.html).

We also use a variety of other third-party service providers for administration, marketing, legal service, technical services, mail carriers, web hosting, communications with customers/users, and social media. Tasks performed by these third-party providers include:

  * tracking the performance of our websites and products;
  * remarketing to website visitors and customers;
  * tracking to measure performance of advertising and emails;
  * saving and managing email opt-ins and customer information;
  * shopping carts and order forms;
  * surveying customer opinions;
  * scheduling consultations and phone calls;
  * signing legal documents digitally;
  * sending email reminders for webinars and coaching sessions;
  * conducting and managing live webinars;
  * sending text message reminders to customers;
  * providing helpdesk and customer service FAQ documentation; and
  * hosting videos on our website.

The name of any such third-party provider which we are using for any of these tasks at any given time may be obtained by requesting it through the contact information provided at the end of this Privacy Policy document.

* **Purposes for Collecting Personal Data**

PSMA collects and uses Data for the following Identified Purposes:

  1. to understand customer needs regarding PSMA’s services; 
  2. to fulfill your requests for products, services or information; 
  3. to communicate with customers and site visitors, when necessary, and to inform customers of upgrades, as well as of other products and services available from PSMA, its affiliates and third parties; 
  4. to allow customers to access limited-entry areas of PSMA’s site; 
  5. to personalize some of our services and products for you and to deliver targeted advertisements and offers from PSMA and third parties; 
  6. to bill accounts and maintain payment records; 
  7. to comply with any applicable law, regulation, legal process or government request; 
  8. to respond to a legitimate claim, or to address our reasonable belief, that you are violating the rights of any third party or any of the agreements or policies that govern your use of the PSMA site or any PSMA product or service; 
  9. to protect the services, products or rights of PSMA, including but not limited to the security or integrity of the PSMA site; 
  10. to identify and resolve technical problems concerning PSMA’s site, products and services; 
  11. to manage feedback, and to respond to and process complaints about products or services; 
  12. to advise you of changes to our products and services; 
  13. to enable us to ensure our websites’ content is delivered in the most effective and efficient way for you and your device; 
  14. to troubleshoot our websites, analyze data, do customer profiling, testing, research, page and message optimization, and process for statistical and internal survey purposes; 
  15. to improve the interactive features of our websites; 
  16. to help keep our websites secure and safe; and 
  17. to measure and analyze the effectiveness and relevance of our advertising. 

If we hire other companies to provide some products or services on our behalf, then we will provide those companies only the Data they need for the Identified Purposes, and we will limit their rights to use and further disclose your Data as appropriate in the course of their work for us.

* **Limiting the Collection of Personal Data**

PSMA limits its collection of Data to only that information which is necessary for the Identified Purposes. PSMA does not direct its site to, nor does it knowingly collect any Data from children under the age of thirteen.

When you visit the PSMA website, a Cookie may be placed on your computer or the Cookie may be read if you have visited the PSMA site previously. PSMA uses Cookies to allow PSMA to determine which products and services you have already purchased so that PSMA does not provide redundant information to you and, if you are a PSMA affiliate, to track PSMA sales made to customers referred by you so that you can receive compensation under our affiliate program.

If you choose not to have your browser accept Cookies from the PSMA website, you may not be able to view all the text on the screens, or to experience a personalized visit, or to subscribe to certain service and product offerings on the PSMA site.

* **Disclosure, Processing and Retention**

PSMA does not sell or rent your Data to anyone else. PSMA will disclose your Data only as follows:

  1. to someone you have designated to act as your agent, for one or more of the Identified Purposes (listed in Section 4, above);
  2. a very limited amount, and in very few cases, to PSMA’s employees, independent contractors, subsidiaries, affiliates, consultants, business associates, service providers, suppliers and agents, acting on PSMA’s behalf for any of the Identified Purposes;
  3. as necessary if PSMA has reason to believe that disclosure is required in order to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be causing injury to or interference (either intentionally or unintentionally) with PSMA’s rights or property, other users of PSMA’s website, products or services, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities; and
  4. to respond to judicial process and provide information to law enforcement agencies or in connection with an investigation on matters related to public safety, as permitted by law, or otherwise as required by law.

In addition, as we continue to develop our business, we or our affiliates may sell or buy other businesses or entities, or we may merge with another company. In such transactions, Data may be one of the transferred business assets. Also, in the event that PSMA or substantially all of its assets are acquired, your Data may be one of the transferred assets.

Your information may be stored and processed in the United States, or in any other country in which PSMA or its affiliates, subsidiaries or agents maintain facilities. By using this website, you consent to any such transfer of information outside of your country. The information we collect from you is processed by staff who may engage in the processing of your payment details. By submitting your Data to PSMA, you agree to the transfer, storing and processing of your information.

After your account becomes inactive (that is, if you request to be removed from our database), PSMA will keep your personally identifiable Data in its archives, unless you request that PSMA delete all data in your account. PSMA will comply with this request, except to retain whatever personally identifiable Data is legally necessary for compliance with applicable law in the United States. Whatever information remains in our archives will then be used only as necessary for tax reasons or to prove PSMA’s compliance with any applicable law.

* **Accuracy of Personal Data**

PSMA will use reasonable efforts to keep customer Data accurate for the Identified Purposes, and for minimizing the possibility of making inappropriate customer decisions based on such information. Customers are responsible for informing PSMA about changes to their Data. PSMA will use new or updated Data it receives from customers to update its own records.

* **Security Safeguards**

PSMA takes all reasonably necessary steps to ensure that your Data is treated securely and in accordance with applicable law and this Privacy Policy. All Data which you provide to PSMA is stored on secure servers. Any financial transactions are carried out on secure sites.

However, the transfer of information via the internet is not completely secure, and we cannot guarantee the security of your Data as it is transmitted to our websites. Therefore any transaction is made at your own risk.

We ask that you keep confidential any passwords that admit you to certain parts of our websites, not sharing those passwords with anyone.

* **Access to Personal Data**

Customers may check their Data to verify, update or correct it, and to have any obsolete information removed. You can also ask to review any of your personally identifiable Data that we have retained, how we have used it, and to whom we have disclosed it at any time by contacting PSMA as indicated below.

Subject to certain exceptions prescribed by law, and provided we can authenticate your identity, you will be given reasonable access to your personally identifiable Data and will be entitled to challenge the accuracy and completeness of the information and to have it amended as appropriate.

You may also ask PSMA to change your preferences regarding how we use or disclose your information, or let PSMA know that you do not wish to receive any further communication from us.

PSMA will afford you a reasonable opportunity to review the Data in your file, if you so request by writing to:

805 Lake Street #295  
Oak Park, Illinois 60301 USA

Or [privacy@perrymarshall.com](mailto:privacy@perrymarshall.com)

If PSMA is not able to provide access to some aspect of a customer’s personally identifiable Data, it will provide reasons for denying access, such as that by doing so would likely reveal personal information about a third party, or that it is confidential commercial information or attorney/client privileged communications, or that the information relates to a breach of an agreement or a contravention of law, or that its disclosure could reasonably be expected to threaten the life or security of another individual.

Customers have the right to request that their personally identifiable Data be removed from PSMA’s database or that inaccurate or incomplete information be amended as appropriate, by contacting PSMA at the end of the Privacy Policy document. PSMA will promptly take action on customer’s request.

Customers may also use the same means of contact to report to PSMA any violation of statute or regulation governing the operation of websites which has affected customers.

* **Policies of Partners and Affiliates**

PSMA’s websites may contain links to and from partner or affiliate websites. Please note that these websites have their own privacy and cookies policies. We do not accept any responsibility or liability for these websites or their policies.

PSMA reserves the right to make changes to this Policy at any time by giving notice on this page (or at another location specified here) of any such changes or revisions. PSMA strongly recommends checking this page often, referring to the date of the last update listed at the top.

 **For any additional information about this Privacy Policy or to make any requests about your personally identifiable Data, please contact PSMA by writing us at 805 Lake Street #295, Oak Park, Illinois, 60301 USA, or by emailing us at[privacy@perrymarshall.com](mailto:privacy@perrymarshall.com).**
